A Guide to the Richmond Forum records, 1987-2010, 2012-2022
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Richmond Forum records, 1987-2010, 2012-2022
The Library of Virginia
44400, 51400, 51799
4.05 cu. ft. (9 boxes)
Richmond Forum
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Richmond Forum, Richmond, Virginia
Historical Information
The Richmond Forum had its origins in 1964 as the Richmond Public Forum. This first incarnation of the Richmond Forum lasted from 1964 to 1980. After a hiatus, the Richmond Forum was restarted in 1987 by Ralph Krueger (1926-1993) and has continued since then. The Richmond Forum brings in noted speakers on politics, business and economy, society and culture, international affairs, technology, entertainment, sports, and other topics.
Scope and Content
Records, 1987-2010, 2012-2022, of the Richmond Forum in Richmond, Virginia, consisting of programs for their annual speakers series and issues of their annual newsletter Podium announcing the Forum's speakers. Programs include schedules, biographies of speakers, photographs, and advertising.
Contents List
- Programs, 1987: Ted Koppel (24 January) Robert C. McFarlane, Hodding Carter, III, and Paul Duke: Iran Yesterday and Today (21 February) Diane Sawyer and Brent Scowcroft: The Tower Commission Report (7 March) Charles Kuralt (27 March) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Programs, 1988: Oprah Winfrey (24 January) Jeane Kirkpatrick, Vladimir Pozner, and Marvin Kalb (20 February) George Will (11 March) Art Buchwald (29 April) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Programs, 1989: William F. Buckley and Charles B. Rangel: Should Drugs Be Legalized (25 March) Carl Sagan (22 April) The program run for 1989 is incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Programs, 1990: Mike Wallace: The Press: Credible or Incredible? (27 January) Bettina Gregory, George McGovern, William Proxmire, Frank Carlucci, III, and William A. Rusher: Perspectives (24 February) Alistar Cooke: A Brief History of American Humor (28 April) The program run for 1990 is incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Programs, 1990-1991: Helmut Schmidt and George S. Vest (13 October) Edwin Newman, Alexander Haig, Edmund Muskie, and William Crowe: Crisis in the Persian Gulf (26 January) H. Ross Perot: Facing the Future (20 February) Art Buchwald and Andy Rooney: Humor and the Press (23 March) James Burke, James Lovell and Frank Drake: Space and Beyond (27 April) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Programs, 1991-1992: Barbara Walters (5 October) Margaret Thatcher (19 January) H. Norman Schwarzkopf and Larry King: The Persian Gulf War: Before and After (22 February) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Programs, 1991-1992: Patricia D. Cornwell, Marc Micozzi, and Victor McKusick: DNA: From Catching Criminals to Constructing Dinosaurs (27 March) Mark Russell: Observations from the Piano (18 April) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Programs, 1992-1993: Terry Anderson and Paul E. Galanti: Free at Last! (October) T. Boone Pickens and Hiroki Kato: Who Has the Greater Commitment to Excellence: the American Worker or the Japanese Worker? (30 January) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Programs, 1992-1993: Joyce Brothers: Why Our Mates Do the Things They Do (27 February) Bill Cosby (27 March) Mikhail Gorbachev and Cokie Roberts (10 April) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Programs, 1993-1994: Chris Wallace, Warren Rudman, Lamar Alexander, and Marvin Cetron: America in the Year 2000 (20 November) Louis Rukeyser, Frank A. Cappiello, and Michael F. Holland: Investment Trends in the 1990s (22 January) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Programs, 1993-1994: George Bush: The World as I See It (19 February) Elizabeth Kubler-Ross: Life, Death and Transition (19 March) Bob Newhart (16 April) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Programs, 1994-1995: Colin Powell: The American Military and a Changing World Order (19 November) Walter Cronkite and Judy Woodruff: American Foreign Policy in the 1990s (21 January) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Programs, 1994-1995: Dave Barry: The Wit and Wisdom of Dave Barry (18 February) Tom Clancy: High-Tech Espionage and the Armaments of the Future (18 March) Jeff Kemp and George Mitchell: Economic Policy and the Future of Business in America (22 April) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Programs, 1995-1996: Gerald Baliles, Brian Mulroney, and Carla Hills: Open Markets and World Trade (11 November) David Hartman, Neil Armstrong, Eugene Cernan, and and Dick Rutan: Space and Flight and the First and Last Men on the Moon (20 January 1996) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Programs, 1995-1996: Calvin Trillin and Alice Trillin: The World According to Trillin (17 February) Charles Kuralt: America Behind the Headlines (23 March) Ed Bradley, David Gergen, Pierre Salinger, Sheila Tate, and Bob Woodward (20 April) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Programs, 1996-1997: Carl Reiner and Dick Cavett (16 November) Paul Volcker and Ray Brady (18 January) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Programs, 1996-1997: Doris Kearns Goodwin and David McCullough: To Preserve and Protect: The Story of the American Presidency (15 February) David Frost and Andrew Lloyd Webber (22 March) Arthur R. Miller, Marcia Clark, Philip K. Howard, Rodney A. Smolia, and Kym L. Worthy: The Legal System in America (19 April) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Programs, 1997-1998: Bill Moyers: Genesis and the New Millenium (15 November) Wynton Marsalis: Jazz in America (17 January) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Programs, 1997-1998: Shimon Peres and Dan Raviv: Peace and Perspectives on the Middle East (21 February) Mary Tyler Moore (21 March) Peter Lynch: Fundamentals of Investing (18 April) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Programs, 1998-1999: John Major: The European Economic Union and the Global Economy (14 November) Robert S. Bennett, William J. Bennett, and Tim Russert: Values in America (16 January) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Programs, 1998-1999: Lou Dobbs and Harry S. Dent, Jr.: The Economy of the New Millenium (20 February) Lily Tomlin (20 March) Robert Ballard and Jean-Michel Cousteau: Discovering Undersea Worlds (17 April) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Programs, 1999-2000: Julie Andrews (13 November) Peter Jennings and Todd Brewster: The Century: A Landmark Program Celebrating the Millenium (15 January) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Programs, 1999-2000: John Krubski, Michael Conners, and Ray Brady: Technology and the New Marketplace (19 February) Desmond Tutu: The Hunger for Transcendence: The Search for Spiritual Values in Today's World (18 March) James Carville, Newt Gingrich, and Tim Russert: Presidential Campaign 2000 Issues and Whatever Happened to the Contract with America? (15 April) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Programs, 2000-2001: John Glenn (11 November) Tom Brokaw (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Programs, 2000-2001: Benjamin Netanyahu and Daniel Schorr (17 February) Frank McCourt: A Salute to Ireland (17 March) William Kelso: The Rediscovery of Jamestown (14 April) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Programs, 2001-2002: Hal Holbrook: Mark Twain Tonight! (10 November) Marc A. Gellman and Thomas J. Hartman (19 January) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Programs, 2001-2002: Dick Clark: Music...the Soundtrack of Our Lives (16 February) Doris Kearns Goodwin and David McCullough: The Art of Writing Presidential Biography (16 March) Madeleine K. Albright, James A. Baker, III, and Gwen Ifill: World Affairs and United States Foreign Policy in the 21st Century (13 April) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Programs, 2002-2003: Ken Burns: The Lewis & Clark Expedition and the Opening of the American West (16 November) Rudolph Guliani (18 January) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Programs, 2002-2003: Benazir Bhutto, Queen Noor, and Gwen Ifill (15 February) Louis J. Freeh: Intelligence, Justice, and National Security (15 March) Fred Thompson: Homeland Security, the Federal Budget, and World Affairs (12 April) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Programs, 2003-2004: Cal Ripken, Jr. (15 November) Robert J. Shiller, Jeremy J. Siegel, and Geoff Colvin: The New Financial Order vs. Stocks for the Long Run (17 January) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Programs, 2003-2004: Candice Bergen: Photographs and Stories (21 February) Mary Robinson: Achieving Human Rights (20 March) Thomas L. Friedman (17 April) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Programs, 2004-2005: Tommy Franks (13 November) Michael Beschloss and Walter Isaacson: Key Presidential Elections and Decisions That Have Influenced the Course of U.S. History (15 January) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Programs, 2004-2005: Tim Russert: A View from Washington (19 February) Fareed Zakaria: Welcome to the Future of Freedom (19 March) Frank Gehry (16 April) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Programs, 2005-2006: Robert Redford and Pat Mitchell (12 November) Sherry Lansing (21 January) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Programs, 2005-2006: Colin Powell (11 February) Tom Wolfe (11 March) Rick Wagoner and Geoff Colvin (8 April 2006) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Programs, 2006-2007: Burt Rutan (11 November) Malcolm Gladwell and Alvin Toffler (13 January) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Programs, 2006-2007: B. B. King (17 February) Jim Lehrer (17 March) Jared Diamond (14 April) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Programs, 2007-2008: Vincente Fox (3 November) Carly Fiorina (19 January) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Programs, 2007-2008: Michael Douglas (16 February) Henry Louis Gates, Jr. (15 March) David Brooks: Current Events & the 2008 Presidential Election (12 April) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Programs, 2008-2009: Schedule for the 2008-2009 season Tony Blair (1 November) Resa Aslan and Jon Meacham (17 January) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Programs, 2008-2009: Smokey Robinson (21 February) Terry Bradshaw and Howie Long (21 March) Michael Pollan and Marion Nestle (18 April) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Programs, 2009-2010: Schedule for the 2009-2010 season Neil DeGrasse Tyson (14 November) Greg Mortenson (9 January) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Programs, 2009-2010: David Plouffe (6 February) Steve Forbes (6 March) Condoleeza Rice (10 April) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Programs, 2012-2013: Schedule for the 2012-2013 season Platon (17 November) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Programs, 2012-2013: Steven Spielberg, Doris Kearns Goodwin, and Tony Kushner (5 January) Bill Clinton (8 February) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Programs, 2012-2013: Mark Kelly with Gabrielle Giffords (9 March) Jane Goodall (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Programs, 2013-2014: Schedule for the 2013-2014 season Ayaan Hirsi, Maajid Nawaz, and Iman Feisal Abdul Rauf (16 November) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Programs, 2013-2014: Dan Buettner (25 January) George W. Bush (22 February) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Programs, 2013-2014: Gordon Brown (15 March) Steve Martin and Martin Short with the Steep Canyon Rangers (19 April) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Programs, 2014-2015: Schedule for the 2014-2015 season Diana Nyad (22 November) Garry Trudeau (24 January) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Programs, 2014-2015: General Keith Alexander and Robert Mueller (21 February) Dr. Ben Bernanke (21 March) Dr. Daniel J. Levitin and Rosanne Cash (18 April) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Programs, 2015-2016: Schedule for the 2015-2016 season Michael Sandel (21 November) Alan Alda (16 January) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Programs, 2015-2016: James Balog (13 February) Julia Gillard (12 March) Russell Wilson and Dr. Henry Louis Gates, Jr. (2 April) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Programs, 2016-2017: Nate Parker (19 November) John Meacham and Doris Kearns Goodwin (21 January) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Programs, 2016-2017: Krista Tippett (18 February) Prime Minister Ehud Barak and Dr. Mohamed ElBaradei (25 March) Ron Howard (22 April) (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Programs, 2017-2018: President Barak Obama: An Evening with the 44th President of the United States (18 November) Glenn Close: Human Characters (20 January) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Programs, 2017-2018: Peter Diamandis: Future Tech: Exponential Change, Infinite Possibilities (17 February) Ambassador Samantha Power: Why America Can't Afford to Look Away (24 March) Joe Scarborough and Newt Gingrich: Perspectives on the Party in Power (21 April) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Programs, 2018-2019: Captain Scott Kelly (17 November) Tina Fey (19 January) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Programs, 2018-2019: Dr. Sanjay Gupta (23 February) Ian Bremmer (23 March) Dr. Temple Grandin (27 April) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Programs, 2019-2020: Bob Costas (9 November) Dave Isay, Catherine Burns, and Brandon Stanton (18 January) Peggy Noonan (22 February) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Programs, 2022: Bob Iger with Kara Swisher (22 January) Gloria Steinem with Zainab Salbi (19 February) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Programs, 2022: Erik Weihenmayer (26 March) Intelligence Squared Debates (30 April) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Programs, 2022: Rhiannon Giddens (21 May) A Conversation with Former First Lady Michelle Obama (7 June) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Podium, The Richmond Forum newsletter1994-1995 through 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Podium, The Richmond Forum newsletter1999-2000 through 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Podium, The Richmond Forum newsletter2004-2005 through 2007-2008 (Box 9, Folder 5)